<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>oneroundpebble.com/james</title>
    <description>James&#39; journey through Heart Surgury and beyond</description>
    <link>http://oneroundpebble.com/james/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://oneroundpebble.com/james/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:10:18 +1100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:10:18 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>One Week Later</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it&#39;s been a week since we left the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James is going really well. If you didn&#39;t know that he&#39;d had surgery less than two weeks ago, you&#39;d never guess it unless you saw the scar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&#39;s not on any pain medication, not even Panadol. It&#39;s truly amazing how little kids recover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scar is healing really well. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 07:55:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2011/14934/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2011/14934/</guid>
        
        
        <category>james heart surgery part ii - 2011</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We&#39;re going home</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing this&amp;nbsp;morning, the nurses removed James&#39; central line (large IV into&amp;nbsp;his neck) which&amp;nbsp;let him without any wall plugs.&amp;nbsp;It was brilliant.&amp;nbsp;The little guy was in a good mood having come off the Fentanyl (a morphine line pain&amp;nbsp;killer) and no&amp;nbsp;longer puking&amp;nbsp;everything we put into&amp;nbsp;him and he was not mobile again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did some little walks and some blowing bubbles&amp;nbsp;through a tube (more&amp;nbsp;fun that&amp;nbsp;you&#39;d expect), watched some Chuggington and had some breakfast.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the doctors rounds this morning, Igor (our sugeon) asked why James couldn&#39;t go home today. No one had any reasons, so it was decided that they&#39;d try and get us out some time in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lyd&#39;s and I were running with &quot;I&#39;ll believe it when I see it&quot; but the doctor was possitive that it would happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily she was right, so just before 6pm tonight, we walked out of the hospital. It was an awesome feeling. We&#39;d been told to expect somewhere between 6 and 9 nights and managed to get out in 5. so after cleaning out our room at Ronald MacDonald House, we jumped in the car and came home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today was a good day, we had James and Nick both having a ball in the play room at the hospital (James didn&#39;t want to walk there initially, but once we got there, couldn&#39;t get him out for well over an hour), and we got to bring everyone home &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 09:51:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2011/14933/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2011/14933/</guid>
        
        
        <category>smiles</category>
        
        <category>james heart surgery part ii - 2011</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pacing</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p mce_keep=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a part of most open heart surgery, Pacing Wires are inserted into the chest cavity when they are completing the procedure. This lets them attach a pace maker if required (if the heart develops an irregular rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully in most cases they don&#39;t need them, but it&#39;s a good precaution. Once the staff are happy with the function of the heart, it&#39;s time to get these pacing wires removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after a morning of&amp;nbsp; vomiting everything that was put into him back up (including all the various medication that James is currently on which they can&#39;t reissue) he was given some more Medazolam. Unfortunately that came straight back at the nurse, so it was decided after that much puke, there wasn&#39;t anything left in the stomach so intravenous it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effect was the same, with a somewhat happier boy watching Mum blow bubbles while the nurses took out the wires and laughed at the patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big event of the afternoon was a fairly big walk out of the room and partway down the hallway, then a good cry to try and get someone to pick him up before walking back to the bed. He wasn&#39;t impressed that Mum and Dad both refused to pick him up, but walked it anyway. [:)]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0cm&quot;&gt;Hopefully we have a better night than last night, James got a fair amount of sleep, but I ended up only getting 4-5 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 08:26:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2011/14932/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2011/14932/</guid>
        
        
        <category>james heart surgery part ii - 2011</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On the Ward</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James was a really tired boy again today, slept quite a bit and was a bit grumpy (can&#39;t blame him for that though).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did have a bit of fun in the afternoon though. The Nurse gave him some Medazolam. Basically, it zonks them out and makes them forget (although it can sometimes make kids a bit hypo). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It put James into a really good mood and he was nice and relaxed when they took out the drains in his chest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He and Lyds had great fun playing with bubbles while the nurses did the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards he started to act like a drunk. Guess that was a bit of an insite to James in 20 years time [:P]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p mce_keep=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 10:13:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2011/14931/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2011/14931/</guid>
        
        
        <category>james heart surgery part ii - 2011</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Out of ICU</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James moved out of ICU on Friday. We where pretty happy, only 24 hours in Intensive Care after major heart surgery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;I stayed with James last night and he had a pretty good night. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He did manage to pull both of his drainage tubes off when he rolled over, but luckly the nurse was right beside the bed and clamped both of them before it had leaked anywhere or got any air bubbles into his chest cavity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke a couple more times, but overal was a pretty good night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today wasn&#39;t quite so good though. James was grumpy all day (I can totally understand it) which made for a pretty long day for everyone.The poor little guy was feeling pretty average this afternoon and was bringing everything back up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&#39;s had some meds to try and settle his stomach now, so hopefully he&#39;ll be on top of that tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2011 08:34:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2011/14930/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2011/14930/</guid>
        
        
        <category>james heart surgery part ii - 2011</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Heart Surgery take 2</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p mce_keep=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today was the big day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 5 cancellations, we got the call at 11am that the surgery was going ahead and to come in as soon as we could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick admission later, James was taken straight off by the Anaesthetist for preparation and then a long wait while the surgeon went ahead with the operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far so good. James is in Intensive Care recovering. They still have him out for the moment and he is getting a little help with the breathing, but he&#39;s stable and doing well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to wake him up and take out the breathing tube. Not sure yet if that is to be done tonight or in the morning, the doctors are yet to decide.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 08:15:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2011/14888/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2011/14888/</guid>
        
        
        <category>james heart surgery part ii - 2011</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Delays</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately after the Pre Admission last week, we had the surgery bumped again. It&#39;s gone from Friday to Monday to Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now James has gotten a cold so we&#39;ve had to let the hospital know and that&#39;s postponed it again. It now looks like the 17th of December for the surgery, assuming that he&#39;s gotten over his cold. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poor little guy. It&#39;s going to make for a pretty crappy Christmas for him if it all goes ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 08:02:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2010/14576/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2010/14576/</guid>
        
        
        <category>james heart surgery part ii - 2011</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Going Back Again</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last 6 months or so, James&#39; heart problems have become a little more serious again. He has a &amp;lt;A title=&quot;Subaortic Stenosis&quot; href=&quot;http://www.rch.org.au/cardiology/health-info.cfm?doc_id=3535&quot; target=_blank mce_href=&quot;http://www.rch.org.au/cardiology/health-info.cfm?doc_id=3535&quot;&amp;gt;Subaortic Stenosis that needs to be repaired sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment we are looking at next Monday for the Surgury, we have pre-admission tomorrow (Wednesday) so we can get the final scans and health check before we go in next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment we don&#39;t know what is going to be done in the surgury, one of the meetings tomorrow is to find out exactly what the surgeon has planned and what sort of recovery times they are hoping for. From what I&#39;ve read, the average for this sort of work is around a week in hospital and then the normal follow up visits, so hopefully we&#39;ll be well and truly home for Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m just trying to figure out the Internet Access while we are in hospital, but I&#39;m planning on using this blog again to give updates on what&#39;s happening while we are in there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 09:09:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2010/14550/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2010/14550/</guid>
        
        
        <category>james heart surgery part ii - 2011</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Definitely a boy</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James has been going really well since we got him home. He’s doing nearly all his normal stuff again. He’s rolling around and as long as we are close by is pretty happy. Unfortunately a week in hospital with Mum or Dad beside the bed most of the time as made him a bit clingy.&amp;lt;p /&amp;gt;While his insides are getting used to the new setup, James has been farting like a trooper. Totally normal given the surgery, but the cheeky smiles we get straight afterwards are definitely a boy thing :-)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 23:18:41 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2009/13801/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2009/13801/</guid>
        
        
        <category>james liver surgery - 2009</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Homeward Bound</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a fairly long day. James wasn’t quite himself. He was pretty grumpy. It was mainly down to food. We were working up to full feeds, but without the solids. This made him hungry most of the time. It was also time to try and stop a couple of the pain relief drugs (the ones they don’t like people to take home) which didn’t help his overall mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mood was definitely lightened when our nurse mentioned that they were considering sending us home if we could get the central line in James&#39; neck out. Needless to say, we were pretty happy if we could get out early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p mce_keep=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the rounds this morning one of the doctors asked why James was still in the hospital. He said that given they weren&#39;t doing much for him anymore that he&#39;d be better off at home. Not one to disagree, I asked for the discharge paperwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James heard the news and was about as happy as his parents and has spent most of the day smiling which a liberal amount of laughing as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 03:27:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2009/13793/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://oneroundpebble.com/james/2009/13793/</guid>
        
        
        <category>smiles</category>
        
        <category>james liver surgery - 2009</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
